Once you see him, nothing can save you.
Sinister is a horror, thriller, mystery film directed by Scott Derrickson.
True-crime writer Ellison Oswalt is in a slump; he hasn't had a best seller in
more than 10 years and is becoming increasingly desperate for a hit.
So, when he discovers the existence of a snuff film showing the
deaths of a family, he vows to solve the mystery.
He moves his own family into the victims' home and gets to work.
However, when old film footage and other clues hint at the presence of a
supernatural force, Ellison learns that living in the house may be fatal.
Ellison Oswalt, played by Ethan Hawke.
Tracy Oswalt, played by Juliet Rylance.
Professor Jonas, played by Vincent D'Onofrio.
Deputy, played by James Ransone.
Sheriff, played by Fred Thompson.
Ashley Oswalt, played by Clare Foley.
Sinister is a 2012 supernatural horror film directed by
Scott Derrickson, who co-wrote with C.
Robert Cargill.
It stars Ethan Hawke as a struggling true-crime writer whose discovery of snuff films depicting gruesome
murders and strange supernatural elements in his new house puts his family in danger.
Juliet Rylance, Fred Thompson, James Ransone, Clare Foley, and
Michael Hall D'Addario are featured in supporting roles.
Sinister was inspired by a nightmare Cargill had
after watching the 2002 film The Ring.
Principal photography on Sinister began in Autumn of 2011 on Long
Island, New York with a production budget of $3 million.
To add to the authenticity of old home movies and snuff films, the Super 8
segments were shot on actual Super 8 cameras and film stock.
It premiered at the SXSW festival on March 10, 2012.
It was released in the United Kingdom on October 5, 2012,
and in the United States on October 12.
Critics praised its acting, direction, cinematography, and atmosphere, but
criticised its use of jump scares and other horror clichés.
It was a box office success, grossing $87.7 million
against its budget of $3 million.
The resulting financial success led to a sequel, released in 2015.
It has since developed a reputation for scariness
and is considered a cult classic.
A 2020 study by Broadband Choices named Sinister the scariest film
ever made, based on an analysis of viewer heart rates.
The film explores themes of drowning, pennsylvania,
usa, writing, child murder, snuff.
The tone is dark and mind_bending and emotional.